[music]
[Instructor] All right, so we have
a really good-looking game now,
with all the cool mechanics,
and animation set up properly,
and now we're going to add
the finishing touches
when we Collide with that Obstacle,
to create a really cool
smoke effect.
So, to do that,
we're actually going to learn
how to use Particle effects.
Now, if you go into your Assets,
under the Course Library,
there's actually a Particles Folder.
And if you expand
the "Particles" Folder,
you can see there's "FX_DirtSplatter,"
and Smoke Explosion.
So, we're going to take
this "FX_Explosion_Smoke,"
and drag it into our Hierarchy,
and then you can see
it creates this really cool puff
when we place it, and you can see
there's actually a little section
down in the bottom right
of our Scene,
we'll make that a little bigger,
and in this Menu you can
actually Play, Restart, or Stop
the animation of our Particle effect.
So if we Play, and we can Restart,
and we can Restart as much as we want,
and we can Stop it,
and we can Play,
so this is just a kind of cool way
to see the Effects,
and how they work. Now, another cool
thing about our Particle System
is that there's a whole bunch
of options
that you can actually change
on the Particle System,
to be able to make it
do different things,
so you can actually go,
and change how fast
the actual Particles
move over their lifetime,
so if we set the Speed
to be ten times as fast,
should move even faster than
before.
Yeah, so it's like a big phh!
That's actually kind of cool,
I'm going to leave that.
So we'll Stop that. So it's pretty cool,
we can set different options, too,
that we want, so we can change
the colors if we wanted to,
we could change how they
actually expand,
all these other different options.
Actually, you know what?
I'm going to set the Speed back
to be 2.
So, there's all these different
ways you can Play around
with Particle Effects, honestly,
you could do 100
different things with them.
I'm not going to go too crazy,
just because the base effect
is really good for now,
so we're just going to use it.
One thing that you want
to be really careful of though,
with your Particle Effects,
is if you open
up the Particle System Menu,
you can actually see
there's a "Play On Awake*,"
and if we set that to true, that would
immediately create a huge puff of smoke
when the game starts. That's not
exactly what we want to happen,
that's not the kind of effect
that we're trying to create,
unless this character were a magician,
then that would make a lot more sense.
So we'll uncheck
the Play On Awake*.
So now,
one thing that we're going to do
is actually put
this FX_Explosion_Smoke
underneath our Player,
as a "Nested" or a "Child" Object.
So that means that it's
an Object that is attached
to another Object, so it
belongs as part of that Object.
So you can actually see Player,
you can see the character,
and you can see the actual
legs that control it.
If we drag
in our FX_Explosion_Smoke on Player,
you can see now, that Player
has a smoke explosion
effect attached to it.
And now, what we can
actually do is when we Play,
we can actually move
our Particle effect around, so,
if we Restart,
see it starts kind of high...
so we can actually...
go, and maybe,
let's just the Y down to 0,
so it's at the bottom
of the Player's feet.
And then we Restart, and there you go,
and now it's closer to the Ground,
maybe we'll make it
a little bit higher.
Something like, not too high, 0.5,
I think is good.
And then Play, cool,
so that's a pretty good position.
So, if you watch at the bottom,
it's like a puff of smoke,
and it creates a really cool effect.
So, now what you're going to do
is you're going to go
into your Assets Folder,
in your Course Library,
go to the Particles Folder,
take the FX_Explosion_Smoke,
and you're actually
going to drag
it directly onto the Player,
so that then it becomes
a Child Object
of that Player.
And then you can go,
and fiddle around
with the FX_Explosion_Smoke
setting its position,
maybe you want to make
it on the head for some reason,
you can go, and mess around
with some of the settings,
but just don't go too wild with it.
And then you're good to go.
Now, it's your turn.
[music]